Guide to the Harry H. Ensign Autograph Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Harry H. Ensign autograph collection
1818-1880
MS 1228
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(1 box)
Miscellaneous autographs and letters of American political and cultural figures, among them John and John Quincy Adams, Daniel Webster, Jefferson Davis, Horace Greeley, and Lydia Sigourney. Also included are eleven letters to James F. Babcock, editor of the New Haven Weekly Palladium, on politics (1840-1866) and seven letters (1866-1872) to R. P. Cowles in New Haven from prospective lecturers.
Ensign, Harry H.
Scope and Contents
Miscellaneous autographs and letters of American political and cultural figures, among them John and John Quincy Adams, Daniel Webster, Jefferson Davis, Horace Greeley, and Lydia Sigourney. Also included are eleven letters to James F. Babcock, editor of the New Haven Weekly Palladium, on politics (1840-1866) and seven letters (1866-1872) to R. P. Cowles in New Haven from prospective lecturers.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
New Haven (Conn.) -- Politics and government; New Haven (Conn.) -- Social life and customs; United States -- Politics and government -- 19th century; Autographs; Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848; Adams, John, 1735-1826; Babcock, James F. (James Fairchild), 1809-1874; Bacon, Leonard, 1802-1881; Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887; Brown, John, 1800-1859; Brown, John; Buckingham, William A. (William Alfred), 1804-1875; Cowles, R. P.; Curtis, George William, 1824-1892; Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889; Dickinson, Anna E. (Anna Elizabeth), 1842-1932; Eaton, William W. (William Wallace), 1816-1898; Ferry, Orris S. (Orris Sanford), 1823-1875; Greeley, Horace, 1811-1872; Hawkins, B. Waterhouse (Benjamin Waterhouse), 1807-1894; Hibbard, R. G.; Holley, Alexander H. (Alexander Hamilton), 1804-1887; Lyon, Nathaniel, -1861; Minor, William T. (William Thomas), 1815-1889; Mitchell, Donald Grant, 1822-1908; Platt, Orville Hitchcock, 1827-1905; Porter, Lafayette G.; Porter, Noah, 1811-1892; Raymond, Henry J. (Henry Jarvis), 1820-1869; Sigourney, L. H. (Lydia Howard), 1791-1865; Stephens, Alexander H. (Alexander Hamilton), 1812-1883; Tyler, John, 1790-1862; Webster, Daniel, 1782-1852; Weed, Thurlow, 1797-1882; Welles, Gideon, 1802-1878; Wheeler, E. S.
- Inventory
  - Autographs and autograph letters
  - Adams, John (1735-1826). Thanking Major General Dearborn "for introducing to me, Mr. Binon whom I find to be a gentleman of Sense and Letters...", 1818 March 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adams, John Quincy (1767-1848). Declining an invitation of the Whigs of New Haven to attend a 4th of July celebration., 1840 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Brown, John (1800-1859). Autograph, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Brown, John, Jr. From John Brown, Jr. to Harry H. Ensign, a hardware dealer in New Haven, complying with his request for an autograph of John Brown. The reply is written on the verso of Ensign's letter. The autograph (enclosed) was cut from a letter by John Brown to his son., 1879 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ensign, Harry H. ALS, 1879 June 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lyon, Nathaniel (1818-1861). To his nephew, John A. Hosler in Webster, Mass. From Fort Riley, Kansas Territory with reminiscences on his army career, comments on the prohibition of slavery in Kansas, and on family news. [4] p., 1859 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mitchell, Donald Grant (1822-1908). To "My dear Madam" from Edgewood [New Haven] offering publishing advice. "Occasional letters upon rural topics, having practical interest, and of a piquant style are always in place." 1 p., 1870 June 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sigourney, Lydia Howard Huntley (1791-1865). To "My dear Sir" asking for his emendations on my 'Boy's Book" 1 p., [1850] September 25 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tyler, John, Pres. U.S. (1790-1862). To President Harrison recommending Richard Adams for appointment as Consul to Havana. Written less than one month before Tyler became President. 1 p., 1841 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence arranged by recipient (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Babcock, James Fairchild (1809-1874) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Buckingham, William Alfred (1804-1875), 1858 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Davis Jefferson (1808-1889), 1840 January 22 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ferry, Orris Sanford (1823-1875), undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Greeley, Horace (1811-1872), 1856 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Holley, Alexander Hamilton (1804-1887), 1857 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minor, William Thomas (1815-1889), 1857 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Porter, Lafayette G., 1857 July 28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Raymond, Henry Jarvis (1820-1869), 1866 February 7 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Webster, Daniel (1782-1852), 1840 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Weed, Thurlow (1797-1852), 1844 July 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Welles, Gideon (1802-1878), 1856 January 24 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cowles, R.P. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Beecher, Henry Ward (1813-1887), 1866 November 25 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Unidentified, 1869 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Curtis, George William (1824-1892), 1869 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hawkins, Benjamin Waterhouse (1807-1889), 1870 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hibbard, R.G., 1870 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - To Dickinson, Anna Elizabeth (1842-1932), 1871 December 16, 1872 August 27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - To Wheeler, E.S., New Haven (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - To Bacon, Leonard (1802-1881), 1880 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - To Platt, Orville Hitchcock (1827-1905), 1880 April 21 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - To Porter, Noah (1811-1892). Re: Chamber of Commerce, 1880 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photographs
  - Eaton, William Wallace (1816-1898), undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Stephens, Alexander Hamilton (1812-1883), undated (Box 1, Folder 12)